quiz = {
    1 : {
        "question" : " Who developed the Python language?\n\n\n",
        "answer" : "Guido van Rossum"
    },
    2 : {
        "question" : "In which year was the Python language developed?\n\n\n",
        "answer" : "1989"
    },
    3 : {
        "question" : "In which language is Python written?\n\n\n",
        "answer" : "C"
    },
    4 : {
        "question" : "Which extension  is the correct extension of the Python file?\n\n\n",
        "answer" : ".py"
    },
    5 : {
        "question" : "What do we use to define a block of code in Python language?\n\n\n",
        "answer" : "Indentation"
    },
    6 : {
        "question" : " Which character is used in Python to make a single line comment?\n\n\n",
        "answer" : "#"
    },
    7 : {
        "question" : " What is the method inside the class in python language?\n\n\n",
        "answer" : "Function"
    },
    8 : {
        "question" : "Which of the following is not a keyword in Python language?  \n"
                     "   1)val \n"
                     "   2)raise\n"
                     "   3)try  \n"
                     "   4)with\n\n\n",
        "answer" : "1"
    },
    9 : {
        "question" : "Which of the following words cannot be a variable in python language?\n"
                     " 1)_val \n"
                     " 2)val  \n"
                     " 3)try \n"
                     " 4)_try_\n\n\n",
        "answer": "2"
    },
     10 : {
        "question" : "Which of the following operators is the correct option for power(ab)?\n"
                    "1) a ^ b\n"
                    "2) a**b\n"
                    "3) a ^ ^ b\n"
                    "4) a ^ * b\n\n\n",
        "answer" : "2"
    },
    11 : {
        "question" : "What happens when '2' == 2 is executed?\n\n\n",
        "answer" : "False"
    },
     12 : {
        "question" : "Which string method is used to check if all the given characters in a"
                     " Python string defined in our program are alphabets?\n\n\n",
        "answer" : "isalpha()"
    },
    13 : {
        "question" : " Which string method is used to check if all the given characters "
                     "in a Python string defined in our program are in lower case?\n\n\n",
        "answer" : "islower()"
    },
    14 : {
        "question" : "Which of the following is not a token defined in Python    \n "
                     "     1)Keywords \n"
                     "     2) Comments \n"
                     "     3)Literals  \n"
                     "     4)Operators  \n\n\n",
        "answer" : "2"
    },
    15: {
        "question" : "Which one of the following is the type of literal collections provided to us in Python?\n"
                     "     1)String literals\n                 "
                     "     2)Numeric literals\n"
                     "     3) List literals\n    "
                     "     4)Boolean literals\n\n\n",
        "answer" : "3"
    },
    16: {
        "question" : "Which of the following type of Python operator will only print True or False in output when we use it in our program?\n"
                     "         1) Assignment operator\n"
                     "         2)Membership operator\n"
                     "         3)Arithmetic operator\n"
                     "         4)Comparison operator\n\n\n",
        "answer" : "4"
    },
    17: {
        "question" : " Why ‘pass’ keyword is use in a Python program?\n"
                     "1)Pass keyword is use to exit the given program.\n"
                     "2)Pass keyword is use to execute nothing.\n"
                     "3)Pass keyword is use to stop the execution of loop.\n"
                     "4)Pass keyword is use to exit the given loop in program.\n\n\n",
        "answer" : "4"
    },
}
